So let's make sure we can see a spinner whilst we are waiting for a response,
Bu yzden, bir yant beklerken bir spikeri grebildiimizden
let's also make sure that if we enter something invalid, we also get a visual error feedback here
emin olalm, ayrca geersiz bir ey girersek sayfadaki grsel bir hata bildirimi almamzn
on the page.
da emin olalm.
Let's start with the spinner and for that,
Spinner ile balayalm ve bunun
I'll go to my auth container and at the very top of it, I'll
iin, auth konteynerine gideceim ve bunun en stnde,
import my spinner component,
spinner bileenimi ithal edeceim,
it's called spinner and we get it from components
buna spinner denir ve biz onu UI
UI spinner spinner,
spinner spinner'dan alrz, gerekten grebiliriz
we can really see how these reusable components make a lot of sense in react here.
Bu yeniden kullanlabilir bileenlerin burada nasl tepki gsterdii ok anlaml.
Now I want to display the spinner as long as we are loading and for that,
imdi, ykleyiciyi yklediimiz srece gstermek istiyorum ve bunun
I need to know if we're loading and we're storing that information in our auth state, for that
iin, ykleyip yklemedmz bilmemiz gerekiyor ve bu bilgiyi auth durumumuzda saklyoruz, nk o
I need to get a piece of that state in my auth container
eyaletteki bir paray almam gerekiyor. benim auth konteyner ve
and that of course is a case for const map dispatch
tabii ki const map gnderme iin bana
excuse me, mapStateToProps, there we get the state and can now map a slice of it to our local props.
bir rnek, mapStateToProps, biz devlet var ve imdi bizim yerel sahne iin bir dilim eleyebilirsiniz.
So I'll return an object where I do this mapping
Yani bu eletirmeyi yaptm bir nesneyi dndreceim ve
and I want to get the loading state for now, so I'll map state. Now on state, we have to access auth
u an iin ykleme durumunu almak istiyorum, bu yzden eyaleti haritalayacam. Artk devlete, birletirilmi redktrler nedeniyle sonuta auth
since this is what leads to the auth reducer in the end due to combined reducers,
redktrne yol aan ey olduu iin auth'a erimemiz
so we have to access state auth and there now, the loading property we set up in our auth reducers state,
gerekiyor. Bu nedenle, devlet yetkisine erimemiz gerekiyor ve u anda, auth redktrleri durumumuzda kurduumuz ykleme
this one here. With that, we got that available here,
zellii, bu Biri burada. Bununla birlikte, biz burada kullanlabilir
we need to pass mapStateToProps to our connect function though
var, biz bizim mapad bizim balant fonksiyonuna mapStateToProps gemek gerekiyor ve imdi burada
and now here in our render method, we can render a spinner.
bizim render yntemi, biz bir spinner render yapabilirsiniz.
So what I'll do is I'll render either the form or if we're loading, the spinner.
yleyse yapacam ey, ya formu ya da yklyorsak, spiner.
So I'll check after the form was created if this props loading is true because if it is, then form
Bu yzden, eer bu sahne yklemesi doruysa, formun oluturulup oluturulmadn kontrol edeceim, eer yleyse, o zaman form artk
will no longer be a const but a let, a variable then form will be equal to the spinner, just like that,
bir const deil, bir izin ver, o zaman bir form, spiner'e eit olacaktr, aynen byle, gstermek
to show a spinner if we're loading, that should be all.
iin Yklyse bir spinner, hepsi olmal.
With that if we enter some data here, no matter if it's valid or not,
Buraya baz veriler girersek, geerli olup olmadna baklmakszn, eer
if I submit this we briefly see a spinner because it's so fast.
bunu gnderirsem ksa srede bir spikeri grrz nk ok hzldr.
Now let's also make sure we see error messages
imdi, yanl veriler gnderirsek ve
if we submit wrong data and to see that, I of course need to take advantage of the fact that I do
hata iletilerini grmemize dikkat edelim ve tabii ki, maazamda potansiyel
store potential errors in my store.
hatalar depoladmdan da yararlanmalym.
So first of all I need to get that error by adding another mapping in the auth container, error
Bu yzden her eyden nce, hatann kapsaycsnda baka bir eleme ekleyerek bu hatay almam
and that should be state.auth.error because I do store any errors in my state here in this error
gerekiyor, hata ve durum byle olmal. auth. hata durumumda bu hata zelliindeki
property and I do that in the auth fail action.
herhangi bir hatay burada sakladmdan ve bunu hata eyleminde yapyorum.
With that, I now need to go back to the auth container and firebase gives us a nice error message, your
Bununla birlikte, imdi auth konteynerine geri dnmem gerekiyor ve firebase bize gzel bir hata
backend might also do this or you craft your own one,
mesaj veriyor, arka ucunuz da bunu
I'm going to take the one from firebase and since we have this message, what I can do is I can display
yapabilir ya da kendinize ait bir ara hazrlyorsanz, ben firebase'den bir tane
an error message. So I can create a new const errorMessage which by default might be null and therefore
alacam. mesaj, ne yapabilirim hata mesaj grntleyebilirim. Bu yzden, varsaylan olarak null olabilecei iin yeni bir
it should be a let too but then I'll add an if statement here,
const errorMessage oluturabilirim ve bu nedenle de bir izin olmal ama
if this.props.error, if we do have to set, if it's not null then error message will actually be some
sonra eer burada bir if ifadesi ekleyeceim. sahne. hata, eer ayarlamamz gerekirse, eer null deilse, hata mesaj
jsx, a paragraph let's say where I simply output this.props.error and there, since firebase
aslnda bir jsx olacaktr, bir paragraf unu syleyeyim. sahne. Hata ve orada, Firebase bana
gives me that, there will be a message property.
bunu verdii iin mesaj zellii olacak.
Again this message property is only available because I'm using the error as it comes back from firebase
Yine bu ileti zellii yalnzca, hata ubuunu geri dndnden ve bir
and that happens to be a javascript object which has a message property,
ileti zelliine sahip bir javascript nesnesi olduu iin hata kullanyorum
this might not be the case for your own backend of course, adjust this to your needs.
nk bu kendi arka ucunuz iin geerli olmayabilir elbette ihtiyalarnz.
I want the output this error message element then, maybe above my form here I'll output error message
Bu hata mesaj elemannn ktsn istiyorum, belki belki de formumun stnde hata mesaj vereceim ve tabii ki bu daha
and of course we could give this more styling, make it red, whatever we want.
fazla stil verebilir, krmz yapabiliriz, ne yaparsak yapalm.
Now before we see something though, we have to ensure that we really store that error,
imdi bir ey grmeden nce, bu hatay gerekten sakladmzdan emin
so I have to go to my auth file in the actions folder and we can access the error message, the error
olmalyz, bu yzden eylemler klasrndeki haksz dosyama gitmem gerekiyor ve hata mesajna eriebiliyoruz, hata nesnesi bu hatada
object we get back from firebase on this error object here by accessing the original response
firebase'den geri dnyoruz Burada orijinal yanta erierek ve aksiyomlardan kaynaklanan nesne burada, burada aksiyomlar kullanyoruz
and that is due to axios, we're using axios here and it simply wraps the response in this error object
ve sadece bu hata nesnesindeki cevab sarar ve orada yine de veriye
and there, still we will have data
sahip olacaz ve bu
and there, we will have this error object.
hata nesnesine sahip olacaz.
You can always confirm this by console logging error response and you will see that you get the same
Bunu her zaman konsol gnl hata yant ile onaylayabilirsiniz ve sadece bir
fields as on a normal response, just with an error code.
hata koduyla normal yantta olduu gibi ayn alanlar aldnz greceksiniz.
With this, if we save everything and we submit an empty form, we get invalid e-mail,
Bununla birlikte, her eyi kaydedersek ve bo bir form gnderirsek, geersiz e-posta alrz,
if I now use that e-mail which we already have in use and I'm not signing in but signing up, we get email
eer u anda kullandmz e-postay kullanrsam ve imza atmam ancak imzalamam varsa, e-posta
exists.
alrz .
Now this clearly is not a nice error message, it would be nicer to get nice text
imdi bu ak bir ekilde ho bir hata mesaj deil, kolayca okuyabileceimiz gzel bir
we can easily read, I guess it does say what's wrong though.
metin elde etmek daha gzel olurdu, sanrm yanl olan sylyor.
You can of course map these codes to your own error messages,
Elbette bu kodlar kendi hata iletilerinizle eletirebilirsiniz. Bu, u an
it is something I won't do here for now but definitely something you can keep in mind as an improvement,
iin burada yapmayacam bir ey ama kesinlikle bir gelime olarak aklnzda
map this to your personal favorite e-mail address.
tutabileceiniz bir ey, bunu kiisel favori e-posta adresinize eleyin.
You can always find out which potential errors you can get by having a look at the firebase auth rest
Firebase yetkisizlik API's dokmantasyonuna buradan bakarak hangi olas hatalar
API documentation here and there, you see common error codes like e-mail not found, invalid password or
bulabileceinizi her zaman renebilirsiniz, e-posta bulunamad gibi yaygn hata kodlar, geersiz ifre veya u
for signing up which we currently tried,
anda denediimiz kayt olmak
that would be e-mail exists, too many attempts or invalid e-mail as you just saw.
iin e-posta var, grdnz kadar ok deneme veya geersiz e-posta olurdu.